Hello everyone, welcome back to the
channel. So today I got some special
product that I'd like to uh show to you.
So for the longest time,
I have a lot of skill except for one,
which is welding.
And uh Seer
contact me and asked to see if I want to
do a review on this handheld welder
machine.
and we're going to do that today. All
right, but first let's me uh open the
box and see what's inside, what come
with it. All right, let's do this. All
right, so
let's see what we got inside the box.
Pretty well packaged.
And straight out of the box is
a whole briefcase.
All right, let's see what's inside the
briefcase. All right.
All right, let's see.
We're going to see what's inside of
this.
Oh, we are upside down.
All right,
let's see what we have here.
So, the unit itself, which is this,
and it come with cable already hook up.
This is the ground. This is where you
plug into the
outlet at home.
There is a I believe
switch here up and on
and adjustable amperage. So we have five
different level
and uh off
and we have what else?
Little brush, little tap thing. I
believe this is a handle for um face
shield. Not face shield but like for
your your eye. So the face shield is on
this side here
manual. Always
does come with a welding rod which uh I
will do a little bit demonstration
afterward.
All right, let's put the thing together
here. Uh, let's see here.
We'll open this up.
[Music]
Yeah, these are very uh basic face
shield.
So if you want some serious uh fish
seal, you need to go buy it yourself.
Also, you need to have some uh personal
uh defense a personal protection
equipment also in order to do welding so
you don't
let me see how this work here.
All right, you have to install this
yourself. I had one heck of a time
trying to install this part right here,
but it does go in like this.
And this piece, you have to install it,
too. So, this is a very basic uh, you
know, face shield/ eye cover.
So, we're going to see how this work.
But to really do the good job, you need
to buy a dedicated helmet for this
welding helmet. But uh we are going to
test this out and see how it work.
Also uh let me go through a little bit
of spec here.
All right. So inside the manual, we'll
have a little bit spec here. You could
pause and read it for yourself if you
want to.
And
let's see what else we got here.
Installation.
little bit more functional of the each
component in here.
And then remember there's five different
levels. So one is for 20 amp, two 45
amp, 7, three for 70 amp, and four for
95, and five for 120. So it go from 20
amp to 120 amp.
120 amp. So, yeah, there's a little bit
of maintenance here, but uh a little bit
of troubleshoot here.
All right, let's go uh uh do some
hand-on practice on this thing.
All right, before we get to uh practical
handon, a little bit disclaimer here.
I'm a novice. I never used a welding
machine before, but I did do a little
bit research on YouTube on how to weld
uh these thick welder.
And uh very be careful. You can get
yourself killed if you not don't wear a
proper uh personal protection equipment
when you're doing weldings
and other stuff, too. So, do a little
bit of research before you practice
this. So I'm I'm just going to do a few
practice uh run see how it work. Uh this
is my first time am I'm am a novice. So
I guess this is designed for for a
beginner DIY DIY for small project
nothing serious I think cuz uh the
maximum current is 120 amp 120 amp is a
lot of current. So like I say, I think
it's operate on DC
and DC even though the voltage is not
that high but the the current will kill
you. So be aware. All right, that's my
disclaimer. Practice at your own uh
risk. All right, let's get to it.
All right, so we are going to I got this
set from Harbor Freight to cover myself.
You should be wearing a pan and long
sleeve and glove so that way you don't
get burned and get socked by the
current.
All right, we're going to try. So, this
thing does come with the rod hang. So,
you press it to insert the
this in here to get it stick in there to
stick.
Just press press and stick it in as far
you can and you should be able to do
well from here. So, like I said, this is
my first time doing this. So,
[Music]
I'm going to connect the
negative here.
This is for ground.
And then
we are going to plug into this.
So I might have to use some extension
cord here.
All right, let's test this out.
So, I'm going to start out with the
probably the middle
number three.
Turn it on.
[Applause]
Heat.
[Music]
Wow.
You can see it's pretty messy. So,
it take a little bit of practice.
[Music]
[Applause]
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]
What you could do?
All right. So, uh, like I said, I was
not, uh, this is my first time ever.
Well, actually, I'm not welding. I'm
testing it out. So, I started out
sparking a little bit to get it start
because once the the metal is hot, then
it will nine easily. You can see from
the video. So I was aiming for this
because I don't have a proper
face shield welding face shield that
auto darkening. So I wasn't seeing what
I'm doing. I'm just go where the the
fire is. So I keep going and going
going. So after I know how to control
where to go
and I try to weld see how the two
pieces. So it's not the best welding job
but it do the job right.
Yeah.
So it will take a lot of practice to do
this. Remember this is a liquid metal
that you convert to weld two piece of
metal together. So they are very
dangerous to handle. So you need to have
proper gear to do it.
All right, thanks for watching. And uh
I will put the link to uh this product
and um I think this is good for small
project around the house or in the
minivan whatever you building. You just
need something to weld really quick. Not
too much of it. You can see how much I
did right here. So a lot of time you
don't need that much. You just need a
little bit here, a little bit there.
Right. All right. Thanks for watching.
I'll catch you on the next video. Bye
for now.